Matthew Church

churchmf@gmail.com 780-966-2257 matthewchurch.ca

Summary

Experienced, passionate, and accredited Software Developer with a focus on user-experience, games, and tools development. C#, Python and C++ programmer with knowledge in operating system concepts, algorithms, and web development. Bachelor of Computer Science acredited on multiple video games ranging from AAA sport titles to epic role playing narrative adventures. Versed in game design and computer graphics concepts. Tools developer with knowledge in database integration, data processing, user interface design, software testing and quality analysis.

Experience

Software Developer

Bioware, Edmonton

June 2014 – Current

C#, C++, SQL, .Net, JS, CSS, Linux

Designed and implemented company wide internal web applications in an agile team. Expanded scalable and intuitive tools utilized by dozens of game teams and occupations including developers, designers, testers, and managers. Improved existing workflows by integrating web applications with game engine and development tools. Experience leading small development team in agile planning and delivering software on time and quality. Lead design meetings and meet with users to improve existing systems.

Software Engineer I

Electronic Arts Canada, Burnaby

July 2013 – June 2014

C++, ActionScript

Full time engineer on the FIFA Games Mode Team. Working extensively with producers, quality assurance and other engineers to deliver high quality features for the game. Participated in agile sprint planning in a large team in order to meet deliverable on a deadline. Tested, wrote and debugged C++ and ActionScript in a massive code base.

Associate Software Engineer

Electronic Arts Canada, Burnaby

January 2012 – September 2012

C++, SQL

Internship on the FIFA Games Mode Team. Worked extensively with producers, quality assurance and other engineers to deliver high quality features for the game. Took ownership of several features both new and old. Tested, wrote and debugged C++ and SQL in a massive code.

Patents

Synchronized Video With In Game Telemetry

US 15076408

Automatically linking recorded streamed video to in-game telemetry to support the QA and debug process.

Presentations and Public Speaking

Improving Workflow and Ensuring Quality with Big Data and Video

Quality Verification and Localization Conference 2017

Improving Content Creator Workflow and Ensuring Quality with Big Data and Video

Frostbite Developer Days 2016

Projects

Aporkalypse

Great Canadian Appathon 3

October 2012 C#, XNA

Designed and implemented a mobile game for Windows Phone 7 in 48 hours for the Great Canadian Appathon 3. Placed in the top 25 and won the category for Best Windows Phone 7 Application.

Umpire Strikes Back

Great Canadian Appathon 2 Entry

October 2011 C#, XNA

Designed and implemented a mobile game for Windows Phone 7 in 48 hours for the Great Canadian Appathon 2. Placed in the top 25 and won the category for Best Original/Experimental Application.

Accredited Titles

FIFA 13

FIFA 14

Zbox 360, PS3, PC

2014 FIFA World Cup Brazil

FIFA 15

Xbox 360, PS3

Xbox 360, PS3

Xbox 360, PS3

Xbox 360, PS3

FIFA 15

Xbox One, PS4, Xbox 360, PS3, PC

Dragon Age Inquisition

Xbox One, PS4, Xbox 360, PS3, PC

Mass Effect Andromeda

Xbox One, PS4, PC

Education

BSc, Computing Science Specialization

University of Alberta

2007 - 2013

Honours and Awards

Academic Excellence Scholarship Technical Achievement Best Original/Experimental Application Best Windows Phone 7 Application University of Alberta
University of Alberta 2009 Game Development Awards
Great Canadian Appathon 2
Great Canadian Appathon 3

Hobbies and Activities

Toastmasters
Global Game Jam
Soccer, Basketball, Snowboarding

Edmonton, Alberta Vancouver, British Columbia Edmonton, Alberta

References On Request